KATERINE GUARIN GUZMAN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT

&

2142, Sydney Australia



(+61) 0416957337



katerine2011@hotmail.com giobannaguarin@gmail.com



katerineguaringuz

SKILLS

- ASP.NET Framework
- ASP.NET Core
- C#
- SCRUM
- SQL Server
- JavaScript,
- IQuery
- TypeScript
- HTML/CSS
- Unit Testing
- Microsoft CRM Dynamics 365
- Azure DevOps
- GIT TFS
- SSRS & SSIS
- WebAPI: REST, SOAP
- SOLID principles
- OOP
- HTML, XML
- CSS, Bootstrap
- MS SQL Server, Oracle

LEARNING

Clean Architecture

EDUCATION

Universidad Distrital Francisco Jose De Caldas, Colombia

Engineering Project Management 2017

Universidad Distrital Francisco Jose De Caldas, Colombia

Bachelor of Electronic Engineer 2014

HOBBIES

Watching movies Hiking Reading

SUMMARY

Enthusiastic and curious Software Engineer with passion for learning and process enhancement. Over 7 years of experience in the IT field across diverse industries such as finance, social and electronic security services. Demonstrating confidence in the ability to skillfully solve problems and optimize code with a methodical approach. Proficient in analyzing, designing, optimizing, and maintaining software systems on the Microsoft technology stack with a specialized focus on backend development. Commitment to continuous improvement, striving for both individual and team success.

WORK HISTORY

Freelancer

03/2023 – 12/2023. **Full Stack .Net Developer.** National Planning Department Colombia Net Core, SQL Server, Restful Web API, Azure DevOps.

09/2021- 02/2022. **Senior Developer** Indra Company: Migration project on Microsoft Dynamics CRM2015 v8.1 to CRM 365 2016 v8.2, Refactoring JavaScript ES5 to ES6 And developing new functionalities.

The Nation Ministry of Finance and Public Credit, Colombia. **Full Stack Software Developer** 03/2020 - 12/2022

- Develop the national financial system using web-based integrated applications in ASP.Net Framework and .Net Core C# MVC.
- Design, develop, test, and implement services, WCF, REST APIs, components, applying SOLID principles, OOP, design patterns, and coding best practices.
- Extensive working experience with C#, EF, LINQ, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS, GIT TFS, IIS, SSRS and MS SQL Server.
- Maintain, troubleshoot, optimize code, and enhance existing systems with a focus on quality, scalability, and maintainability.
- Collaborate with different teams to design, develop, test, and maintain various modules/services, ensuring integration with other systems.
- Regularly communicate with both technical and non-technical groups as part of product/project support and the Scrum methodology within a continuous integration/continuous deployment (CI/CD) framework using Azure DevOps.

Achievement: Implemented optimization of services resulting in a significant decrease in information loading time.

The Agency for Reincorporation and Standardization (ARN), Colombia **Full Stack Software Developer** 07/2017 - 12/2018

- Develop applications on .NET Framework and Microsoft CRM Dynamics 365.
- Interpret and develop specifications, technical requirements, and user stories.
- Design, develop, and maintain components, applying SOLID principles, OOP, design patterns, and coding best practices.
- Programming in JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, ASP.NET MVC, and C#.
- Build and consume RESTful WebAPI, develop plugins in C# using .NET SDK assemblies for Dynamics 365, utilize XrmToolBox and Plugin Registration Tool.
- Develop and demonstrate proficiency in MS SQL Server, SSRS, SSIS ETLs, and implement Continuous Integration within a Scrum methodology using Azure DevOps TFS/Git.

Achievement: Automated financial support liquidation with 98.6% accuracy, resulting in a 20-day reduction in manual report generation time.

Bogota Secretary of Social Integration, Colombia. **Software Engineer** 01/2019 – 03/2020

- Develop data applications specialized in generating and integrating information about all social projects in Bogota.
- Developing and implementation of Data Modelling, DWH, ETLs, boards, data flows and flow charts, statistics, T-SQL queries and materialized views for Power BI base PL/SQL Oracle.
- Experience with AWS services, SSIS, SSRS, Pentaho, FTP servers reports, Power BI, Scrum methodology and continuous integration supported by Jira.

Achievement: Successfully developed an ETL for a Big Data project related to childhood monitoring.

Supervisa S.A, Colombia. **Engineer manager**

06/2015 - 07/2017

- Analyze, manage, and coordinate technological electronic security projects utilizing Software-as-a-Service (SAAS) applications, with focus on PHP and MySQL.
- Lead projects and guide a team of technicians following PMI guidelines.
- Calculate and evaluate management indicators, producing reports on deliveries, compliance, and quality performance.
- Participate in functional design, strategy training, and model requirements to meet the specific needs and requirements of stakeholders.